SWARAJ SANGARE

SAP | PAYROLL SPECIALIST

5 war aj. sangar c @ yanoo.co.	3	Swaraj.sangare@yahoo.cor
--------------------------------	---	--------------------------

+91 9921440668

Pune, Maharashtra

https://www.linkedin.com/in/swarajsangare

PROFILE

Senior Payroll and Account Specialist with 11 years experience.

Consistently meet operation goal along with report generation, report analysis, error resolution.

Have always prioritized the work and planned in proper manner.

Proactive self starter with minimum supervision also team oriented and co-operative.

EDUCATION

2008 B.COM

University of Pune, Pune

2004 H.S.C

M.I.T Jr. College, Pune

2002

S.S.C

M.I.T School, Pune

SKILLS

- SAP payroll system
- Star payroll system
- Oracle application system
- Team oriented and co-operative
- Calm and professional under pressure
- Proactive self-starter

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Marathi

EXPERIENCE

Process Specialist Feb 2023 – Till Date Infosys BPM, Pune

- To manage and perform payroll task as per timelines, reviews and validates the inputs, process payroll information in line with company policy and procedures.
- Executes payroll tasks as per prescribed guidelines and timelines in order to meet SLA targets.
- Support the team leader in the daily huddles, provides inputs on processes to the team in order to ensure delivery predictability.
- Executes transactions in order to meet quality standards, conducts quality check programs as part of the quality plan in order to ensure adherence to process steps.
- Handles to resolve escalations at the process level in order to ensure high customer satisfaction.

Senior Customer Service Executive Apr 2018 – Aug 2022 Top Source Global Solutions Ltd, Pune

- Planning and execution of UK Payroll processing weekly and monthly payroll for clients based in UK with payroll processing reports (pre-live and post-live).
- Ensuring adherence to the checklist generate ad-hoc reports to analyze payroll data.
- Ensure payroll processes are effectively and efficiently adhered to maintain and publish periodic dashboard, MIS reports.
- Reconciliation of payroll, auditing periodic review of process and training documents.
- Managing multiple payroll clients ensuring that all outputs delivered to client meet the stringent standards set out in the SLA.
- Submission of forms P45, P46 to HMRC regularly, preparing and sending form P32 to all the clients every month.
- Calculating and processing statutory pay such as maternity pay, paternity pay sick
 pay and adoption pay and keeping track for these details updating clients on
 regular basis.
- Processing statutory deduction such as student loan, attachments, PAYE and NI.

Senior Accountant Aug 2014 – Mar 2018 Trends Technology, Pune

- Provisional balance sheet /finalization of balance sheet, monthly received data, monthly expenses data, P/L account.
- Manage annual audit and other compliance audits to ensure financial records are maintained as per compliance.
- Issue cheque, bank statement, vendor payment, outstanding bill payments, cheque deposit, online transfer, vendor payment, outstanding bill payments.
- Responsible for all aspects of accounting accounts payable, accounts receivable, general ledger entries, bank reconciliation, expenses reports.
- As per the guidance by CA organizing and maintaining all financial records.

Process Associate August 2012 – July 2014 Steria India Ltd. Pune

- Checking and collecting timesheet data and payroll information
- Entering data into oracle application system.
- Calculating pay raises, wages, benefits, commission, shift payments and overtime compensation.
- Issuing tax forms and related documentation and assisting employees to complete them.
- Maintaining accurate records of payroll documentation and transaction.
- Resolving issues employees have with timesheet, pay slip and other payroll
 matters
- Changing employee bank records when necessary to process payments accurately.